Three, two, one. Go!
I won.
Let's do it again, please.
Okay.
I'll definitely win this time.
20 YEARS LATER
HONEY, CALL ME. I WANT TO TALK TO YOU
I WANT TO TALK TO YOU
Lucía, are you on your phone during class?
Ruth, honey, call me. Okay?
Latest news on Alejandro Huelva,
the nine-year-old boy
who disappeared on October 23rd.
Groups of volunteers,
mostly neighbors from Mieres,
are collaborating with the Civil Guard
in a search that,
so far, has not been successful.
The authorities have set up
a special phone number
that any citizen can call...
- Alejandro!
...about the case completely anonymously.
The number is 984 555 6704.
Now, on to other news.
The employment rate in the last quarter...
THE TRUTHERS
Hey, all good?
MOM:
RUTH, PLEASE
CALL ME. IT'S IMPORTANT
Large black coffee with milk, please.
- What is it?
- Ruth...
It's Mom.
- What?
- Mom fell down.
What? She what?
Where did she fall?
Mom is dead, Ruth.
Last call for passengers
on flight 817 to Madrid.
Please proceed to the boarding gate.
URGENT
MISSING
He went out on his bike
like every afternoon,
but hours went by,
and he didn't come back.
And... he still hasn't come back.
We know he's out there.
If someone sees him, please...
If that kid hasn't turned up yet...
What a tragedy. The town is in shock.
They go out looking for him every day,
but I doubt there's much hope.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
What happened?
We need to be strong.
Me especially.
What's the Civil Guard doing here?
Okay. Thanks, Carlos.
Guys, I'm sorry, but...
Even if it was an unfortunate accident,
we need to document what happened.
So what happened?
She slipped in the shower.
Apparently, she'd been drinking.
Impossible.
- Excuse me?
- No.
She didn't... My mother didn't drink.
She'd been drinking lately.
She did.
Ruth, it seems that your mother,
at around midnight,
went upstairs to the bathroom
to take a shower.
Shall we go upstairs?
Sure.
Your father was upstairs, in the attic,
and noticed that your mother
was taking a while to come out.
I called her, and she didn't answer,
but I could hear the water running, so...
I had to break down the door.
She was... motionless.
She wasn't breathing.
We believe that when she slipped,
she fell onto the screen, and it broke.
She hit her head on the floor and...
Well, she died quickly.
Sorry, you can't touch anything for now.
Sorry, it's just that...
My mother never locked the doors.
She didn't like it.
She never let me lock them.
She'd freak out on me whenever I did.
Honey.
It's as if we're talking
about somebody else, isn't it?
Ruth.
I don't recognize her.
You haven't been here in almost two years.
How could you recognize her?
- Patience.
- Patience. We've got no other choice.
I was just telling your father
we still have paperwork,
routine stuff left.
Well, you know.
But as soon as we have
the toxicology report
and confirm everything's in order,
the body will be made available
for the funeral, the viewing, and so on.
I hope it'll be as soon as possible.
In the meantime,
anything you need, I'm here, alright?
Let's go.
Martín, you know where to find me.
- Thanks again.
- No problem.
- Good afternoon.
Well, if you need anything,
you know where I am.
Dad.
Did something happen yesterday?
Why do you say that?
Because Mom called me.
Several times.
I was having a bad day and didn't answer.
And she sent me messages too.
What did she say?
That she wanted to talk.
We had a bit of a fight.
Why?
Because I didn't like her drinking.
I think that's why
she locked herself in the bathroom.
So she could keep drinking
without me saying anything.
But her glass was downstairs.
What?
Her glass. She didn't take it with her.
She left it downstairs.
She must have forgotten it. She was drunk.
What does it matter?
It matters. It matters, Dad.
She called me, and I didn't answer.
And I wanted to call her today.
I was going to call her today, and now...
Ruth, I know you don't like
talking on the phone.
But if I'm calling or texting you,
it's because it's important.
Don't worry, I'm not going to bug you
about coming home anytime soon.
I know flights are expensive and all that.
It's about your father, Ruth.
Your father is not the man
you used to know.
Your father is... He's a different person.
For some time now.
I didn't want to tell you
so you wouldn't worry.
But...
Sorry.
I thought I heard him coming.
Ruth.
Your father...
Your father is scaring me.
He spends all day locked up in the attic.
I can't explain it to you now, but...
I'm afraid that one day
he'll do something crazy.
Call me, please.
I love you.
CIVIL GUARD
DO NOT ENTER
Dad?
Did you sleep well?
A bit runny.
That's how you like them, right?
- There you go.
- Thank you.
Do you want anything else? Some juice?
No, I'm not very hungry.
Can I help you with anything today?
No, don't worry.
We can't do much until the Civil Guard
gives us the go-ahead.
I can do the shopping if you want.
Or I can help you in the greenhouse.
I've been neglecting
the greenhouse lately.
Why's that?
I've been busy.
You're retired, Dad.
Do people stop being people
when they retire or what?
Eat up.
Last night I heard your mother's voice.
In a dream or...?
No.
On your phone, I guess.
Did she leave you a message?
No. They were old voice messages.
Are you sure?
Why?
I'm your father, honey.
I can tell when you're lying to me.
I wish you'd also notice when I drop hints
because I don't want
to talk about something.
Why won't you tell me
what she said to you?
Because it was between us, Dad.
Yeah, right. As usual.
God forbid I get involved in your world.
You were always like cats and dogs,
but if I stepped in,
you'd close ranks
and there was no way to get through.
It's not a big deal.
Well, that's over now, honey.
We can't have secrets anymore.
Your mother is gone. Do you understand?
Yes, Dad.
Thank you very much.
Ruth.
The Civil Guard Sergeant called.
The coroner is done.
They're giving us Mom back.
Did they find anything strange?
What were they supposed to find?
She drank and fell down. That's it.
Can I help you?
No need, honey.
Dad! Let me help you.
I don't need your help.
Give it to me.
I'll race you whenever you want.
Let's see who wins.
Better stick to laps, don't you think?
That wouldn't be fair.
No one can compete in the water
with a mermaid.
This mermaid is a little out of practice.
What are you doing?
Throwing away this rubbish.
Those are Mom's creams.
Rubbish.
And those bastards
charge a fortune for them.
You're swearing a lot lately, aren't you?
Those sons of bitches ruin people's lives
and then take their money.
Who are we talking about?
Big Pharma.
Do you know what they've done
in the United States?
They have half the country
hooked on opioids.
Not to mention fentanyl.
They drug them, ruin them,
and turn them into zombies.
What does that have to do
with Mom's creams?
You know how they make them?
They experiment on animals.
I know.
And on people.
People?
On children.
Children like Alejandro.
Haven't you heard?
Impossible not to hear about it.
He has disappeared
from the face of the earth.
And do you know
who's moved in here recently?
The headquarters
of a big American pharmaceutical company.
What a coincidence.
There's no such thing
as coincidence, honey.
I can send you links.
There are thousands of videos, articles,
people fighting to make this known.
Dad.
Okay.
I don't know why I'm surprised.
You're just like your mother.
Hello, Sergeant. How are you?
I'm Ruth, Martín's daughter.
My father told me
that you have the coroner's report
and that it says it was an accident.
- That's right.
- Right.
Well, I... Tell me if I'm out of line
or if I'm overstepping,
but I'd like to know if it's possible...
for me to see the report.
Or...
Or the photos or something because...
Well, it's just that
I'd like to know exactly...
what happened.
And...
Hello?
You want to see a copy of the report?
Yes, if it's possible. I'd like to.
No problem.
Okay.
WAKE UP
What exactly is that substance?
Adrenochrome is obtained
by adrenalizing the blood of children.
Children are abducted.
Then they're terrorized, tortured,
and subjected to atrocities
to saturate their blood with adrenaline.
It's consumed as a drug
that rejuvenates the elites.
Of course, those who can afford it.
And supposedly,
it's mixed with another well-known drug.
Indeed. Fentanyl.
Fentanyl, which, by the way,
comes from Ukraine.
What a coincidence.
It's all connected.
Why don't we have more information
about this terrifying subject?
Because the media
doesn't want the truth to be known.
Only a handful of us
actually know the truth.
I'm sorry.
Hi, Grandma.
Hello, dear.
Hi, honey. How are you?
How awful, dear.
How's your father?
Like all of us. In shock.
Thank you.
I haven't eaten anything for two days.
I imagine your mother
lying on the floor and...
I don't understand
how this could have happened.
Well, I don't know.
Did you know she was drinking?
Yes.
Your mother hadn't been okay lately.
She was feeling down. Sad.
I didn't know anything.
I don't know. It's so weird for me
to talk about this with you.
Especially in the past tense.
Was it because of my dad?
Look, your father...
Don't mention your father,
because your father... is acting weird.
Who knows. Retirement.
It's likely not sitting well with him.
And the pandemic.
That was hard for him and for everyone.
Did you know that we had to take
your mother to get vaccinated in secret?
She was so worried.
She was worried that he would find out.
She didn't know
how he was going to take it. Bah.
But you...?
I don't know, do you think that...?
Do you think they argued,
or he got violent or something?
Maybe he...
I don't really know.
You know that your mother
didn't tell me much, or anyone else.
Here you go.
The copy of the report.
There are some pictures
of how we found her on the floor.
If I were you, I wouldn't look at them.
FORENSIC REPORT
PROBABLE CAUSE OF DEATH:
SEVERE HEAD TRAUMA FROM ACCIDENTAL FALL
Ruth, I'm so sorry.
My deepest condolences.
She worked us hard.
All day long doing laps, right?
She was very strict, but easy to love.
She missed you so much.
Well.
Sorry, do you know
who my father is talking to?
That man? He's part of his search team.
Search team for what?
I don't know if you've heard,
but a child's missing.
And the neighbors have organized
search teams to look for him.
That's Mariano, the new commissioner.
Luis, from the repair shop.
And that's Alfonso, the police doctor.
What?
You know, the doctor...
What's it called?
Coroner.
The coroner.
- Excuse me.
- Of course.
"Alfonso."
CORONER ALFONSO GARCÍA MARÍN
Dear Lucía, may God watch over you.
We are going to miss you.
Especially your husband and your daughter.
They are not alone.
The good Lord will be with them
until they are reunited with you.
Faith is so necessary
at times like this.
It's so important to believe
that someone is waiting for us...
Dad, who's that woman
over there by the pillar?
We only remember God...
No idea.
But we remember...
She was also at home. At the wake.
...how orphaned those who don't believe are.
Or those who worship false idols.
Or those who let themselves
be led astray by absurd beliefs
in search of who knows what.
Why do we have to put up
with so much bullshit?
To false prophets,
the merchants of the temple,
and the falsely enlightened ignorant,
the Lord has words for them.
I am the path.
And the truth.
And life itself.
Arón!
Arón?
Ruth.
It's been forever.
Yeah.
Hey, are you still dealing?
I'll see if I can find something,
but only because it's you.
I don't do this anymore.
I've moved up in life.
I'm a cleaner now.
Okay.
Here you go.
Thanks.
Sorry, I wanted to go to the funeral.
But your mother had it in for me.
It didn't seem right.
But now I regret it.
You don't go to funerals for the dead,
but for the living who stay behind.
I was really grateful to those
who came to my father's funeral.
Don't worry.
It's not like my mother
was a big fan of yours.
She needed someone to blame
for her daughter losing her way.
What are you talking about? I'm not lost.
But my life isn't going
in a straight line anymore.
How beautiful.
No, seriously.
I get why your mom hated
the boyfriend who got you into weed.
Boyfriend?
Well, fuck buddy. Okay? Fuck buddy.
I don't think she liked that either.
But the one giving me
dirty looks lately is your dad.
Why is that?
I don't know. But he was less creepy
when he was a Civil Guard officer.
When we met up, he'd even offer me
a security gig or something.
Short shifts, good money.
But since I started working at Certyx...
Is that the new pharma company?
It's not that he doesn't say hello.
He looks like he wants to kill me.
What?
I don't know.
Maybe my father has a screw loose,
but I'm the one who's going crazy now.
He's acting weird, you know?
Different.
So?
I've even wondered whether...
I'm not the same as I was
a few years ago, either.
You're the same.
Damn.
How come?
Colon cancer survivor.
How about that?
I don't know. I had no idea.
Yeah, well, we haven't talked in a while.
I wasn't going to tell you in an email.
It's true that this little bag
has changed my life a bit, but oh well.
Some days it feels like
the most fucked-up thing in the world.
And other days, I'm thankful for it.
Because it's proof
that I came close to dying, and I didn't.
That always makes me want to celebrate.
Oh really?
What?
It's just that right now, with the bag on...
What? Can't you do it?
I don't know. I really don't know.
I haven't hooked up with anyone
since I've had it.
And why is that?
It doesn't make me feel very attractive.
To be honest.
You're hotter than ever.
Really?
Look at this huge building.
This is where I work.
It's been a fun night.
- Take care.
- You too.
What are you doing?
Can't you see?
So soon?
The sooner it's done,
the sooner we can get on with our lives.
The sooner
you can get into the attic, right?
What do you do up there, Dad?
I read. I watch videos. I inform myself.
That's what everyone should do.
And you need to lock yourself in for that?
I don't like people
meddling in my business.
You were the same.
You made us put locks
all over the fucking house.
The "fucking house"?
Yes.
I was a fucking teenager, Dad. Unlike you.
You've never talked to me
like that before.
Maybe that's what you needed, honey.
A few hard truths.
I don't recognize you.
But you're still the same.
You even had to leave
your mother's funeral halfway through.
Thank you.
OXIDATION PROCESS
ADRENALINE ⇒ ADRENOCHROME
Ruth, I thought maybe
you'd like to keep Mom's phone.
It's almost new.
And yours clearly isn't.
Thank you.
Damn, this one is expensive.
Yes.
That really bothered her.
She asked me
why I had spent so much money.
Everything bothered her.
Since when?
At first, she was angry with you,
because you had left.
Because you hadn't finished your studies.
Because you were out there,
doing God knows what.
But what's the point of being angry
with someone who's not there?
The only person
she had in front of her was me.
The only person to blame for everything.
She blamed me
for not being stricter with you.
It's always easier to blame someone else.
It was a very hard time.
But don't worry.
I'm much better now.
I'm leaving.
Dad.
Do you have the phone's password?
You don't need it.
I did a factory reset yesterday.
And everything that was on it?
Your mother is dead.
Why would she need what was on it?
Why would you need it?
Me?
I don't.
- Never mind.
- Sure.
Do you think you can find anything
that might have been inside?
I can try to recover
whatever was in the cloud.
But the shop in town
will do it better, for sure.
In the town everyone knows my father.
So what?
Ruth, what the hell is going on?
He spends all day locked up in the attic.
I can't explain it to you now, but...
I'm afraid that one day
he'll do something crazy.
Something crazy at your father's age
could be anything, Ruth. Anything.
A divorce. Or buying a convertible.
But she said she's afraid, Arón.
My mother wasn't afraid of anything.
Yeah.
But you hadn't seen her in a while.
Damn, I know. But she's my mother.
She used to go to the bathroom
with the door open.
She didn't like closed doors
and she didn't like secrets.
And I'm sure she didn't like my father
locking himself in the attic.
What if she went in there
and saw something?
Something my father
doesn't want anyone to see.
And they argued
and that's why she called me.
And that's why she got killed.
Hang on, Ruth. Let's see.
Have you talked to the Civil Guard?
All the civil guards
are friends of my father.
I mean, I don't know.
Do you think I'm imagining things?
No, I don't know. I don't know, Ruth.
Is that why you're staying
a few more days?
I need to know
that what I'm imagining is not true.
- We're in.
- What's in there?
It says there are 200 photos.
That doesn't seem like a lot to me.
Yeah, it's a new phone.
I think she got it for Christmas.
Nothing. There's nothing here.
Couldn't there be a folder?
Something he didn't want you to see?
What's that?
There's one. "Untitled."
Close your eyes.
Why?
- Just in case.
- Just in case what?
Imagine there are nudes
of your mother or your father--
Come on, Arón.
Or both of them naked.
You don't want to see that.
- You're so dumb.
- And neither do I, honestly.
But if that's what I have to do
to marry you, I'll do it.
I'm kidding. Come on. Close your eyes.
Okay. Go ahead.
Can I open them?
Who's this?
Fuck.
Fuck. I knew it.
- I knew it.
- What's going on?
It's that woman that was both
at the wake and the funeral.
I asked my father who she was,
and he said he didn't know.
Who the fuck is she?
I don't know.
Only your mother and your father know.
Well, I want to know too.
I'm going to find out.
How are you going to find that out?
I'll show the pictures to my father
and make him tell me the fucking truth.
And you'll do that on your own?
Shit, Arón.
You were blazing in the van, seriously?
I was nervous. But I can handle it, okay?
Hi, Dad.
Do you remember Arón?
I invited him to dinner.
Good evening.
Great.
Sorry, I haven't been cooking much lately.
I just make quick meals.
Don't worry, Martín.
This is Michelin-star level for me.
Do you eat a lot of junk?
In the morning I clean shit,
and at night I eat it.
Maybe that's where the cancer came from.
Dad.
No, it's not your fault.
It's the chemicals
they put in everything nowadays.
And they do it knowingly.
They make you sick,
and then sell you the cure.
Meanwhile, they ruin public healthcare,
so we all have to pay for it.
"They"?
The people you work for.
Martín, I mop floors.
You work for murderers.
And kidnappers.
Don't forget that.
Do you think this is funny?
Wait, Martín, let me get this straight.
You think my bosses
are to blame for my cancer?
I don't know if your bosses
are specifically to blame, but...
Well, you mean the big companies.
And the governments.
Martín, come on.
Who else is to blame?
Well, it's always easier
to blame someone else.
I wish someone was to blame.
I wish cancer was created somewhere,
and we could all go there,
destroy everything
and get rid of that shit.
But that's not how it goes, Martín.
- Oh, really?
- No.
How does it go, then?
You got it? Tough shit.
And you never know
when it's going to come back.
So you take all that fear,
and you swallow it.
But you don't swallow it.
You light it up, right?
You toke, lie on the couch,
and you do nothing.
And let them do whatever they want.
And what do you do, Dad?
I ask myself questions. I investigate.
I go further.
That's what you do with your friend?
The one at the wake
you said you didn't know?
You see, Dad,
Mom had pictures of you two on her phone.
Walking around town.
What are you doing, honey?
Nothing. I'm investigating. Just like you.
Who is she?
Her name is Berta.
Great.
- Who is Berta?
- Berta is a friend.
A friend.
Yes, at my age,
one can also make new friends.
But it's easy for people in town
to get the wrong idea.
That's why I prefer to keep quiet.
- And where?
- What?
Where? Where did you meet her?
On the internet.
On Tinder?
No. On research forums.
Who goes on those forums, Dad?
A lot more people than you think.
- Oh, really?
- Yes.
Most people keep quiet because...
Why?
Because it's not easy
to talk about certain things.
Because you can lose people along the way.
Is that what happened to you?
With Mom?
It could be.
Berta has lost a lot of people.
She lost her husband.
She lost custody of her children.
And right now she feels very lonely.
As a friend, I try to keep her company,
spend time with her.
I'm trying to help a friend.
Is that wrong?
What do you think?
I understand why you're like this, really.
But regardless of everything going on
in his head, he's still the same person.
I mean, he's a civil guard,
but he's a good guy.
Even in that story he's got in his head,
he's cast himself as the hero
saving kids from the evil elite.
Hey, this room brings back memories.
It'd be exciting doing it here,
with your dad next door.
- Like in the old days.
- Oh, Arón.
Do you know how to force open a door?
I need to get into the attic
and see what my mother saw.
And why should I care?
I don't know anyone else
who can break a lock.
And I can?
Why? Because I used to sell weed?
I don't know. I was just wondering
if you could help me.
Ruth, I'm not a criminal.
I know, Arón. I thought
maybe you might know someone.
Who do you think I hang out with?
Who do you think I am?
Forget it, Ruth. It doesn't matter.
First, we take out the cylinder carefully.
Like this. Make sure the clips don't snag...
Hello?
I'm sorry, Arón. I was...
Hey, have you seen my badge over there?
Your what?
It has my picture and a barcode.
And a blue ribbon.
I can't find it anywhere.
Where did you leave it?
I always leave it hanging in the van.
But maybe I accidentally left it
at your place yesterday.
Does that badge let just anyone
into the pharmaceutical company?
Yes, of course.
- I see.
- Ruth, what are you thinking?
- It's weird, isn't it?
- What do you mean?
Don't you think it's weird
that you come here and lose your badge?
- Did you leave the van unlocked?
- It must be somewhere.
Don't worry.
I'll see if I can get a duplicate. Bye.
LAS VEGAS
PUBLIC SCHOOL
My ex-wife is not well.
I had to get a restraining order.
And they granted it.
Without hesitation.
Because she's dangerous.
She's dangerous.
In what way?
Well, she lost her mind.
She was...
She was a wonderful woman.
She was great. She was...
But she lost it.
She got sick.
She went through a severe depression
that lasted for many months.
It was terrible.
And she locked herself up.
She isolated herself
and started to believe in nonsense.
She said that birds were not birds.
That they were watching us.
That planes were spraying
nanotechnology particles to control us.
Suddenly, some really bad guys
were controlling everything.
And she had to defeat them.
Then all the pain in the world would end.
That's when she became obsessed
with the disappearances.
With the missing children.
There was no way to convince her
that it was all nonsense?
I wish.
She started obsessively
watching my kids. Our kids.
When they came home,
she'd search them for cameras.
She was on that damn control all day.
She renewed her gun license
and had them all over the house.
And, instead of stopping there,
it just got worse and worse.
My ex-wife, when she was in the military,
was an expert on munitions.
It was like she might blow
something up at any moment.
I know that...
One day I will see her name
in the newspapers. I know it.
My father is like a different person.
I know what I'm going to tell you is hard.
But get away from him.
Stay away, as far as you can.
What are you doing?
Practicing.
Is there a problem?
I've never seen you shoot before.
What about the gun? Don't you
have to give it back when you retire?
You never know
when you're going to need it.
Good night, Ruth.
Who were you talking to? Is it bad news?
No. Just my employer in Berlin.
Where are you going?
We're still looking for Alejandro.
I'm going to the lake.
You want to come along?
You loved it when you were little.
Okay.
We have combed the entire forest
and we have found nothing.
If he had gotten lost, if he had fallen,
or if he had died,
we would have found the body.
So, what are we doing here?
- There are tunnels.
- Tunnels?
Yes. They're hundreds of years old.
During the war, the Maquis used them
to go see their families in the town.
Look.
See?
Do you know what's on the other side now?
- What?
- The pharma company.
Right.
Shall we?
NO SWIMMING
Enough already. Okay, Dad?
What if the entrance to the tunnels
was in the lake?
They said there were spills
a few years ago.
That's why no one goes swimming.
People use it as a dump.
But what if it's a cover-up
to keep people out of the water,
so they don't find the tunnels?
I'll have to come back with a wetsuit.
You know what?
It won't be necessary.
What are you doing?
- Looking for the tunnels.
- What?
It's full of garbage!
Where are the tunnels, Dad?
This way? Or that way?
What are you doing?
The same as you.
The same crazy things you do every day.
It's not funny, is it?
I don't see anything.
Maybe this way?
What's wrong?
Fuck.
- I cut myself.
- I told you.
Take me home.
What?
Do you know how much crap is down there?
I know. In fact, I warned you.
I need to clean the wound
or it'll get infected.
It's nothing.
I want to check something up there.
Hurry up. It's going to rain.
It's like the only thing you care about
is your fucking obsession with that kid.
We just buried Mom,
and you're at it again, dammit.
I don't know, I feel like...
Like Mom's thing pissed you off
because it interrupted
your search for two days.
Are you telling me that I don't care
about my wife's death?
Why do you care so much about that kid?
What's up? Do you want to impress her?
Who?
Your friend, Berta.
Is she the one who brainwashed you?
I don't know. Tell me.
Are you in love or something?
I've only ever loved one woman,
your mother.
Despite the drinking.
Despite the fact that, all of a sudden,
she became a Sunday mass devotee.
Your mother hadn't been well
for a long time, Ruth. Since you left.
Sure. Now it's my fault, right?
Do you know why I left, Dad?
Because I couldn't take it anymore.
Because I wanted to quit swimming,
and you wouldn't let me.
And I wanted to live my life.
Your mother adored you, Ruth.
You were the light of her life and,
all of a sudden, you left her in the dark.
Are you still surprised
that she took to drinking?
Maybe she did because she couldn't stand
being next to a grumpy old man
who was getting crazier every day
with his shitty conspiracies.
Do you know how hard it is to love someone
who looks at you like that?
Who doesn't respect you anymore?
Who doesn't love you anymore?
Who suddenly only sees
a useless old man in you?
I guess it's also my fault
that you're so sick in the head, right?
I'm completely sane.
Sane as ever. I'm awake.
It's you and the rest of you
who prefer to live in ignorance.
Ignoring the suffering,
the pain of those kids and their families.
I'm done. I can't deal with you going back
to your fucking insanity again and again.
I'm not crazy!
If there was an epidemic
of missing children,
it would be on the front page
of every newspaper, dammit!
You're so naive, honey.
Do I have to explain to you at this point
how the world works?
I'd rather think you're naive
and not something worse.
Are you going to start suspecting me too?
Sure, everyone is bribed except you.
Right, Dad?
Everyone is an idiot except you.
Have you looked at yourself in the mirror?
Have you seen what you look like?
Because it's not precisely
the look of a genius.
You don't look like that enlightened man
who knows the truth
and everyone has to follow.
You're just a fucking old man locked up
in an attic doing God knows what.
That's what you are, Dad.
You want to know what I do in the attic,
don't you?
Is that why you tried
to force the door yesterday?
Have you been spying on me?
- Great.
- Where are you going?
- You'll get lost! Ruth!
- Let go of me!
- Leave me alone!
- Ruth!
Ruth.
Ruth!
Stop!
Leave me alone!
Ruth!
You lost consciousness,
but you're fine now.
You'll need a few days of rest,
or this ankle will suffer.
If it hurts,
take a painkiller every eight hours.
And drink the infusions your father makes.
He's good with herbs.
But mainly, rest. We don't want
that ankle to heal badly, okay?
Okay.
What the fuck are all those cameras
doing around the house?
Are you spying on me
or were you spying on Mom?
What are you talking about?
Why would I spy on you? Don't be silly.
Silly. I'm being silly now.
I put them up for security.
Because I was afraid
those people would come after us.
For God's sake.
You see? I knew you wouldn't believe me.
That's why I didn't tell you.
Who is going to come after us, Dad?
Who? The pharma company people?
And the politicians. And the police.
They can bribe anyone,
even the least expected.
Think about it for a moment.
They do those atrocities to kids.
They're capable of doing anything
to any of us who bother them.
And they know I'm investigating them.
Not long ago, they caught me
snooping around their building.
A guard asked me for my ID. I refused.
But they know who I am and where I live.
What were you doing there, Dad?
The tunnels end there. In their basement.
Look, I can't take it anymore. I can't.
I can't stay here and keep a poker face
while you tell me about tunnels
and kidnapped kids.
I can't take this.
You're not listening to me.
They're very dangerous.
The only one following me
in her car is your friend.
She's protecting you, Ruth.
From what?
She follows you to make sure you're okay.
Being my daughter makes you a target.
Were the cameras recording
the night Mom died?
Of course.
And what do they show?
They show Mom going into the bathroom.
That's it.
Does the Civil Guard know?
Yes. I gave them everything.
It was the first thing I did.
Well, you didn't tell me.
Because you wouldn't believe me.
That's why.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Let me show it to you, okay?
This video is from when your mother
was already in the bathroom.
The day... she died.
That's right.
But there's no sound.
No, of course.
We don't know if my mother answered.
What if my dad's just putting on a show?
That would mean that your father
considered the cameras
to execute a plan
that would give him an alibi
and allowed him
to kill your mother in cold blood.
Do you believe that?
No. But my mother
locks herself in and falls.
- How does she fall?
- The alcohol.
My mother couldn't drink that much.
Okay.
This footage is from a few days earlier.
It might shock you a little.
She had clearly been drinking
that day too.
- Please, turn it off.
- Yes. Of course. I'm sorry.
Maybe I'm sticking my nose
where it doesn't belong.
Is everything okay at home?
We're here for whatever you need.
Okay?
How could you even think of driving
with your foot like that?
Didn't you hear the doctor?
Do you want to have an accident?
Want me to lose you too?
I needed to know.
Know what?
That your mother drank
until she passed out?
Is that what you needed to know?
That's exactly
what I wanted to protect you from, honey.
From those images.
You didn't need to know that.
I don't want you
to remember your mother like that.
I'm sorry.
Promise me you'll rest
and stop overthinking.
Take a shower and relax.
Drink the herbs. They'll do you good.
Ruth, do you need anything?
Honey, are you okay?
Ruth, say something.
Ruth?
Are you okay? What's wrong?
It's so fucking weird. I was fine.
Then I drank the fucking infusion
my dad gave me and started feeling dizzy.
- You know?
- Okay.
I began to lose my balance.
Stumbling. Like my mother in those videos.
So I started thinking
that maybe my dad gave her something.
Something his friend, the coroner,
left out of the fucking report.
- That's why it's not there.
- Wait.
Hold on, because right now
I don't understand anything.
And I'm a little high.
I thought in the video you can see
your dad knocking and your mother not...
Who told you that?
Because you can see it,
but you can't hear anything.
Maybe it was all a charade.
Knocking on the door. Knocking it down.
And when he entered and saw
that she couldn't move or anything,
he killed her in cold blood, you know?
Ruth, are you listening to yourself?
Do you hear what you're saying?
He drugged me. I couldn't stand up.
I don't know. Maybe you smoked.
- I didn't smoke.
- Did you take something else?
Nothing.
I took...
I took the painkiller for my foot
and whatever they gave me at the station.
Well, maybe that's it.
Why don't you believe me?
What were you talking to my father about?
I saw you two whispering.
Ruth, your father is worried sick
about you. That's all.
- Are you sure?
- Yes.
Didn't he offer you a job?
Look, that's enough.
Okay, Ruth. That's it.
Next time you think your dad's
trying to kill you or he's seeing aliens,
call someone else, okay?
Because I'm tired of it, Ruth.
I'm tired of rushing over
every time you need a fuck,
some weed, or a locksmith.
Right.
So I'm the one
taking advantage of you, right?
Everything you do,
you do it selflessly. Right, Arón?
Not because you think
maybe you and I can have something again.
I'm done, Ruth.
Ruth.
Open the door.
Are you okay?
Do you want me to call Dr. Velasco?
FEBRUARY 26, 2024
ALFONSO ALWAYS MAKES US SMILE
CIVIL GUARD
I'm here to talk to Sergeant Ballester.
He's not answering. Please wait.
- I can't wait. It's urgent.
- Hey!
Hey!
Excuse me.
You can't be in here.
Ruth! What are you doing?
What are you doing?
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, Dad.
Can you make me
one of your infusions, please?
Of course.
UNKNOWN CALLER
ACCEPT
Ruth, this is Sergeant Ballester.
They told me you came to see me.
Yes.
I guess you saw your father in my office.
I think we need to talk.
Why?
Your father came to see me this morning
to tell me that he thinks...
that somehow you could be involved
in your mother's death.
He thinks you're connected
to the pharmaceutical company
that set up a branch in the area,
and might be working with other people.
That there's no such thing as coincidence.
Anyway. The ramblings of someone
who's lonely and has too much free time.
We've been seeing this a lot lately.
MISSING BOY
CHECK LAKE
ARE THEY WORKING FOR THEM?
I just want you to know that for us,
and for anyone with half a brain,
the case is closed and there was no crime.
It was an accident.
Each and every piece of evidence points
to it being an unfortunate accident, yes.
Then why?
Why what?
Why make up all those things?
Because I guess it's very hard to accept
that you've lost the person you love...
in such a silly way.
It's always easier to blame someone else.
It's not easy to know
what to do with so much pain.
I think those ideas
make your father feel special, useful.
But I just wanted to warn you.
He has the conviction of a fanatic.
And a fanatic is...
the most dangerous kind of person.
Be careful with him, please.
Thank you.
Dad?
Dad.
I'm sorry.
- Hey. Stay away from him.
- I'm sorry.
I just want to talk.
You almost killed him, dammit.
Let me explain. Everything's fine.
Dad.
He's afraid of you. Can't you see?
And no wonder.
- Damn it, Dad.
- Give me your hands.
- If you want to talk, it'll be tied up.
- What?
We can't risk you attacking him again.
Dad.
Do as she says, honey.
I thought you had something to do
with Mom's death.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry, Dad.
I didn't realize. I...
I didn't want to hurt you, really.
What are you going to do?
Are you going to call the Civil Guard?
What is it?
- Fuck!
- This is not necessary.
Come here.
Right now we have a problem
with your daughter, Martín.
We don't know what she's seen
or hasn't seen in the attic.
We have to act now.
We have to get to the tunnels.
We need to find the children.
Who the hell is it now?
It's the doctor.
He must have come to see Ruth.
Tell him to leave.
What's that, Dad?
Is that Arón's badge?
Dad! No! Dad!
Dad, please, don't leave me here!
Shut up, dammit.
- Dad!
- Let's go with the words...
Help!
Will you shut up?
- Dad!
- You will shut up.
...in Asturian.
And today's nice word has six letters.
Inma? No?
Let's calm down a bit.
Hey, calm down. I'll take care of it.
That nice word doesn't smell very good.
I'll wait for you in the car.
No. Rebound.
Dad, what are you going to do
with Arón's badge?
Is that what Mom saw?
What you're about to do?
Is that why you deleted
everything on her phone?
She went into the attic too.
She found out what we're going to do
and she went nuts.
And then, yes,
she started drinking more than usual.
But I don't think it was an accident.
I think someone killed her.
Do you really think
I had something to do with it?
I know you'd never
do anything to your mother.
But maybe they're using you to try
to implicate me and get me out of the way.
I didn't think so at first, but all this,
your mother's death just after they saw me
wandering around their building,
is too much of a coincidence.
Mom fell.
I know it's hard to accept,
but we have no choice.
I know it's terrifying,
but making up stories doesn't help.
I told the doctor you were sleeping
and to come by this afternoon.
He'll untie you.
Dad.
Dad!
Fuck.
Help!
Help me, please!
SEARCH CONTINUES FOR ALEJANDRO HUELVA
He's in the lake.
Arón, please, listen to me.
I know I've said a lot of nonsense lately.
I know. But this isn't.
My father has your badge
and he'll use it to get into the building.
He may already be inside.
And that's not all.
He has a gun and explosives.
The woman who's with him
was in the army and knows how to use them.
They're headed to the basement.
They think there are children hidden
in secret tunnels or something.
God knows what they're capable of doing
to find them.
I'm on my way.
But I might not get there in time.
I need you to believe me.
Please, Arón. Please.
...and he'll use it
to get into the building.
He may already be inside.
And that's not all.
He has a gun and explosives.
Careful.
Wait.
Let's go.
I'll go.
All good.
Let's do it.
Stop. You can't go in.
My father is inside. I have to go in.
Arón. Hey, are you okay?
Let's try the next wall.
They must be behind it.
Dad.
Ruth! What are you doing here? Go home.
No. You're coming with me.
I can't, honey.
The boy is not here.
Remember I cut myself
on some metal at the lake?
It was Alejandro's bike.
The boy is there.
He's drowned with the bike. I'm sure.
You'd say anything
to make me change my mind.
No, Dad. If you don't believe me,
we can go to the police.
I'm sure they'll find him.
He's in the lake.
Even if that were true,
it's not just Alejandro.
It's all the other children.
Those who were,
and those who'd come after.
Don't you see that,
by uncovering the truth, we can save them?
I understand you, really.
But you don't have to save anyone.
You don't have to save any children.
You don't have to change the world.
You don't have to be a hero.
Isn't it enough for you to be my father?
Because I do need you.
Let's go. Let's think of another plan.
Let's come back another day.
Whatever you want.
I'm not leaving you anymore.
I'll stay right by your side. I swear.
I swear, Dad.
I love you.
- No! Dad!
- Let's go! Ruth!
Today we woke up
to the sad news that Alejandro Huelva,
the boy who disappeared a month ago,
has been found dead in Lake Caldas.
Alejandro's body
was found trapped in some debris.
A tragedy that adds
to the deaths last week
of Martín Arce and Berta Martínez,
victims of the explosions
caused by themselves
in the basement
of the pharmaceutical company Certyx.
Apparently, both believed
that in the basement
there were tunnels where they would find
Alejandro and other missing children.
A conspiracy theory that,
in recent months,
has been gaining a lot of traction--
ONE YEAR LATER
Hello.
You're Martín's daughter, right?
The one from the pharma company.
Tell me something. He's not dead, is he?
What?
It's all a cover
so he can keep investigating, right?
So they'll leave him alone.
No one can know.
Because the police and the media
are all in on it.
It's clear they experimented on that boy
and then threw him in the lake.
What are you talking about?
Don't you realize
that doesn't make any sense?
Right.
You can't talk, right?
Does it put you in danger?
I get it.
But one day the truth will come out.
I think your father
will bring everything to light.
He's an inspiration for so many people.
Tell him that from me.
Cool.
NO MORE LIES
FREE OUR CHILDREN NOW
WE WANT THE TRUTH
NO MORE LIES. WAKE UP!
Subtitle translation by: Olga Garrido